<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Actually relevants on</title><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/actually-relevant/</link><description>Recent content in Actually relevants on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/actually-relevant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/AG/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/AG/</guid><description>OPINION OF ADVOCATE GENERAL
RANTOS
delivered on 20 September 2022 ( 1)
Case C‑252/21
Meta Platforms Inc., formerly Facebook Inc.,
Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, formerly Facebook Ireland Ltd.,
Facebook Deutschland GmbH
v
Bundeskartellamt,
intervener:
Verbraucherzentrale Bundesverband e.V.
(Request for a preliminary ruling
from the Oberlandesgericht Düsseldorf (Higher Regional Court, Düsseldorf, Germany))
(Reference for a pre bject – Consent given to a dominant undertaking responsible for processing – Article 6(1)(b) to (f) – Lawfulness of processing – Processing necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the controller or by a third party – Processing necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which the controller is subject, the protection of the vital interests of the data subject or of another natural person or for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller – Article 9(1) and (2)(e) – Special categories of personal data – Personal data which are manifestly made public by the data subject – Articles 51 to 66 – Powers of the national competition authority – Reconciliation with the powers of data protection supervisory authorities – Adoption of measures under competition law by an authority located in a Member State other than that of the lead authority for the supervision of data protection)</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/CJEU-Huber/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/CJEU-Huber/</guid><description>JUDGMENT OF THE COURT (Grand Chamber)
16 December 2008 ( *)
(Protection of personal data – European citizenship – Principle of non-discrimination on grounds of nationality – Directive 95/46/EC – Concept of necessity – General processing of personal data relating to citizens of the Union who are nationals of another Member State – Central register of foreign nationals)
In Case C‑524/06,
REFERENCE for a preliminary ruling under Article 234 EC from the Oberverwaltungsgericht für das Land Nordrhein-Westfalen (Germany), made by decision of 15 December 2006, received at the Court on 28 December 2006, in the proceedings</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/CJEU-Question-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/CJEU-Question-3/</guid><description>97 As regards, in the first place, point (b) of the first subparagraph of Article 6(1) of the GDPR, that provision provides that processing of personal data is lawful if it is ‘necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract’.
98 In that regard, in order for the processing of personal data to be regarded as necessary for the performance of a contract, within the meaning of that provision, it must be objectively indispensable for a purpose that is integral to the contractual obligation intended for the data subject.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/CJEU/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/CJEU/</guid><description>Provisional text
JUDGMENT OF THE COURT (Grand Chamber)
4 July 2023 ( *)
REQUEST for a preliminary ruling under Article 267 TFEU from the Oberlandesgericht Düsseldorf (Higher Regional Court, Düsseldorf, Germany), made by decision of 24 March 2021, received at the Court on 22 April 2021, in the proceedings
Meta Platforms Inc., formerly Facebook Inc.,
Meta Platforms Ireland Ltd, formerly Facebook Ireland Ltd,
Facebook Deutschland GmbH
v
Bundeskartellamt,
intervener:
Verbraucherzentrale Bundesverband eV,</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/Contract-under-Brussels-I/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/Contract-under-Brussels-I/</guid><description>Concerning, in the first place, the interpretation of the concept of ‘matters relating to a contract’ within the meaning of Article 5(1)(a) of Regulation No 44/2001, it is important to note that that concept must be interpreted independently, regard being had to the general scheme and objectives of the regulation, in order to ensure that it is applied uniformly in all the Member States. That concept cannot therefore be taken to refer to classification under the relevant national law of the legal relationship in question before the national court (see by analogy, inter alia, Case C‑26/91 Handte [1992] ECR I‑3967, paragraph 10, and Case C‑265/02 Frahuil[2004] ECR I‑1543, paragraph 22).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/DPC-Final-FB-Dec-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/DPC-Final-FB-Dec-22/</guid><description>Data Protection Commission
21 Fitzwilliam Square South
Dublin 2, Ireland
1. INTRODUCTION AND PROCEDURAL B****ACKGROUND
PURPOSE OF THIS DOCUMENT # 1.1 This document is the Decision (“the Decision”) of the Data Protection Commission (“the Commission”), made in accordance with Section 113 of the Data Protection Act, 2018 (“the 2018 Act”), arising from an inquiry conducted by the Commission, pursuant to Section 110 of the 2018 Act (“the Inquiry”). 1.2 The Inquiry, which commenced on 20 August 2018, examined whether Meta Platforms Ireland Limited (formerly Facebook Ireland Limited) (“Facebook”) complied with its obligations under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council) (“the GDPR”) in respect of the subject matter of a complaint made by Ms.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/DPC-IG-Dec-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/DPC-IG-Dec-22/</guid><description>In the matter of the General Data Protection Regulation DPC Inquiry Reference: IN-18-5-7
INTRODUCTION
This document is a Decision (“the Decision”) of the Data Protection Commission (“the Commission”) made in accordance with Section 113 of the Data Protection Act 2018 (“the 2018 Act”), arising from an inquiry conducted by the Commission, pursuant to Section 110 of the 2018 Act (“the Inquiry”).
The Inquiry concerned a complaint made to the Belgian Data Protection Authority: L&amp;rsquo;Autorité de protection des données (the “Belgian DPA“) on 25 May 2018 in respect of the Instagram service (the “Complaint”).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/EDPB-Final-IG-Dec-22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/EDPB-Final-IG-Dec-22/</guid><description>Binding Decision 4/2022 on the dispute submitted by the Irish SA on Meta Platforms Ireland Limited and its Instagram service (Art. 65 GDPR)
Adopted on 5 December 2022
Adopted Having regard to Article 11 and Article 22 of its Rules of Procedure (hereinafter “EDPB RoP”)3(#ftn3),
Whereas:
(1) The main role of the European Data Protection Board (hereinafter the “EDPB”) is to ensure the consistent application of the GDPR throughout the EEA.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/EDPB-Guidelines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/EDPB-Guidelines/</guid><description>Guidelines 2/2019 on the processing of personal data under Article 6(1)(b) GDPR in the context of the provision of online services to data subjects
Version 2.0
8 October 2019
The European Data Protection Board
Having regard to Article 70(1)e of Regulation 2016/679/EU of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC,</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/Excerpts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/Excerpts/</guid><description>CJEU # Questions 3 and 4
![[CJEU#^0c0001]] ![[CJEU#^10a2d0]]
&amp;hellip; [[CJEU^97]] 97 As regards, in the first place, point (b) of the first subparagraph of Article 6(1) of the GDPR, that provision provides that processing of personal data is lawful if it is ‘necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract’.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/Facts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/Facts/</guid><description>CJEU #  The dispute in the main proceedings and the questions referred for a preliminary ruling
26 Meta Platforms Ireland operates the online social network Facebook within the European Union and promotes, inter alia via www.facebook.com, services that are free of charge for private users. Other undertakings of the Meta group offer, within the European Union, other online services, including Instagram, WhatsApp, Oculus and – until 13 March 2020 – Masquerade.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/Reference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/Reference/</guid><description>The following questions on the interpretation of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation, ‘the GDPR’) and Article 4(3) TEU are referred to the Court of Justice of the European Union for a preliminary ruling:</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/Structure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/Structure/</guid><description>REQUIREMENTS # Processing must be for: - &amp;#39;Proper&amp;#39; - Performance - Contract between DS and DC **And** DC must prove that - Not merely useful -&amp;#34;main subject matter&amp;#34; CANNOT be achieved Main subject matter hard to establish Mixed contracts Anciliary obligations should count Impossibly of performance is too high of a standard Reasonable expectations as a mitigation?
Average or specific data subject If average: minorities?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/To-follow-up-on/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mnov88.github.io/amethyst/Actually-relevant/To-follow-up-on/</guid><description>Look into different type of contracts e.g. ==obligation of means== vs result, Haaskjold 449
See also subsidiary prestations, p 653
See also difference between ytelse and prestasjonshandling, p 672
Some contracts require no performance actively, if conditional</description></item></channel></rss>